Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin slavery collection, 1728-1973.
Rudin (Gail and Stephen) Slavery Collection,
- Series XVI: Sale, Hire, Purchase, Collateral Documents
  - Sale of Eighty-Four slaves, April 1, 1847; Location: Charleston, South Carolina Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 41, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 243
  - Buyer purchases five young women, February 27, 1847; Location: New Orleans, Louisiana Format: Ptd Doc (Box 17, Folder 54)
    Rudin # S - 778
  - Slave Bill of Sale for an Eleven year-old boy, July 23, 1847; Location: Louisiana (Box 17, Folder 55)
    Rudin # S - 28
  - Expense Bill for the Sale of Slaves including the Handbills, Advertising the Sale, etc., September 25, 1847; Format: MDocS (Box 12, Folder 32)
    Rudin # S - 468
  - Grandfather Deeds Granddaughter a Negro Child, December 20, 1847; Location: Robertson County, TX Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 33)
    Rudin # S - 239
  - Alabama, Judgement for slave Bob keeping one dog contrary to law, January 5, 1848; Format: MDS (Box 12, Folder 33)
    Rudin # S - 1043A
  - Letter written to a woman slave dealer concerning the purchase of a cook and servants for a plantation., January 31, 1848; Location: Nashville, Tennessee Format: ALS (Box 12, Folder 34)
    Rudin # S - 305
  - Receipt for the Purchase of Three Girls and their Passage to New Orleans, June 11, 1849; Location: New Orleans, Louisiana Format: MDOC (Box 12, Folder 35)
    Rudin # S - 298
  - Reverend Gooch Pursues a Debt that Might Involve a Slave in Payment, November 15, 1849; Location: Logan County, Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 34)
    Rudin # S - 569
  - Buying Slaves in 1850 Texas, March 22, 1850; Location: Van Buren, Texas Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 546
  - Sale for "an unsound Negro", February 19, 1851; Location: Charleston, South Carolina Format: Ptd Docs (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - Missouri Sheriff's Slave Sale Broadside, June 16, 1851; Location: Marion County, Missouri Format: Ptd DOC (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 433
  - Letter, Mississippi slave owner attempts to sell "Bill", November 11, 1851; Location: Format: (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 183
  - One Slave, Two Mules, One Wagon, One Buggy and Harness to be Taken in Lieu of a Deb, December 23, 1851; Location: North Carolina Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - Two Slave Bills of Sale Pertaining to the Same Slave Woman Maria and Her Son, Charles - Sold Twice in Four Years, 1851; February 9, 1847; Location: Augusta, Georgia Format: MDocS (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 494
  - Man Desperate to Buy-Back His Best Slave, April 12, 1852; Location: Natchez, Mississippi Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 442
  - Sale of four slaves with printed newspaper ad, January 3, 1853; Location: Florida Format: MDocS (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 47
  - Slave Hire Contract and time sheet, January 14, 1853; Location: Mobile and Ohio Railroad Format: (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 185
  - Slave Broadside - "Sale of Valuable Negroes!" - Annotated by Someone who Probably Bid at the Auction, but with No Prices Realized, March 8, 1853; Location: Montgomery Format: Ptd DOC (Box 24, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 501
  - Reward of a slave as a bonus for winning a lawsuit, signed RH Marr, March 28, 1853; Location: New Orleans, Louisiana Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 650
  - Pair of Slave Bills Purchasing a Black Woman named Betsy; by Two Different Owners Within Six Months, August 27, 1853 February 4, 1854; Format: MDocS (Box 13, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 558
  - Purchase Order for a Male Slave and for a Cook, November 28, 1853; Location: New Orleans, Louisiana Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 241
  - Hiring of 14 Slaves, December 16, 1853; Location: Leon County, Florida Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 58)
    Rudin # S - 234
  - Partially printed receipt for hire of a man, January 2, 1854; Format: Ptd Doc (Box 13, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 620
  - Availability of a Slave Woman for Sale, January 21, 1854; Location: Augusta County, Virginia Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 208
  - Letter regarding the availability and going prices for female slaves, signed Stephen Westmore, July 18, 1854; Location: New Orleans, Louisiana Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 936
  - Slave Auction Broadside: "60 Very Choice Sugar Plantation Hands" - Annotated with Prices Realized, March 8, 1853; Location: New Orleans Format: Ptd DOC (Box 24, Folder 5a)
    Rudin # S - 500
  - Slave Purchase, April 23, 1855; Location: Butler, Alabama Format: ALS (Box 17, Folder 59)
    Rudin # S - 328
  - Payment to Slave Auctioneer, August 3, 1855; Format: MDocS (Box 13, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 349
  - Slave Broker Discusses the Sale of a Slave Family, October 31, 1855; Location: Charleston, South Carolina Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 581
  - Bill of sale containing names and ages of 123 Georgian Slaves sold for $61,000, December, 1856; Location: Glynn County, Georgia Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 60)
    Rudin # S - 1019
  - Slaves for hire Document, four girls, 1857; Location: Florida Format: (Box 13, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 54
  - Female Slave Hire, January 3, 1857; Location: Petersburg, Virginia Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 13, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 259
  - Slave Sale Notice, May 6, 1857; Location: Herrick Co.? (Box 13, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 180
  - Slave-catcher's receipt for "Hunting boy Joe with dogs", October 15, 1857; Format: MDS (Box 13, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 1043B
  - New Orleans Slave Sale, February 13, 1858; Location: New Orleans, Louisiana; Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 17, Folder 61)
    Rudin # S - 246
  - Newspaper Advertisements of Slave Auction Sales, April 27, 1858- July 9, 1858; Location: DeSoto County, Mississippi Format: Ptd DOC (Box 40, Folder 35)
    Rudin # S - 296
  - Sale of Slaves Broadside, 1858; Location: Missouri Format: Broadside (Box 17, Folder 62)
    Rudin # S - 48
  - Letter discussing sale of slaves and price of land, July 4, 1858; Location: Lexington, Mississippi Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 651
  - Document of Slave given as security for a bond, July 26, 1858; Location: Tennessee (Box 17, Folder 63)
    Rudin # S - 110
  - Bill of Sale by slave dealers, 1859; Location: Louisiana (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 92
  - Plantation Inventory Listing Slaves Purchased Between 1829 and 1849, 1859; Format: MDoc (Box 13, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 522
  - Auction-Slaves for Hire, 1860 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 50
  - Slave Auction Broadside - Sale of 28 Slaves, January 14, 1860; Location: 161 Gravier Street, New Orleans Format: Ptd Broadside (Box 18, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 256
  - Missouri Slave Bill of Sale for Louisa and Her Daughter, March 14, 1860; Location: Bird's Point, Missouri Format: MDocS (Box 13, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 413
  - Pre-Printed Slave Sale, September 8, 1860; Location: Montgomery, Alabama Format: Ptd DOC (Box 13, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 371
  - Slave Auctioneer's Pre-Printed Bill of Sale for a Slave Girl, September 17, 1860; Location: Richmond, Virginia Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 13, Folder 24)
    Rudin # S - 549
  - Debt covered by one piano and one slave, January 16, 1861; Location: Tennessee (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 93
  - Document divides slaves, September 2, 1861; Location: Bourbon County, Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 887
  - Certified Copy of Indenture recording division of slaves, cattle, land, etc. Copy signed by William Huff, 1861; June 16, 1868; Location: Fort Bend County, Texas Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 36)
    Rudin # S - 578
  - Free black man, FW Hobson, requests authority to hire an African American, January 8, 1862; Location: Richmond, Virginia Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 37)
    Rudin # S - 896
  - Agreement to pay a substitute confederate soldier with a slave, August 21, 1862; Location: Texas Format: MDocS (Box 13, Folder 25)
    Rudin # S - 804
  - Letter with Instructions for the Immediate Sale of Two Slaves, September 9, 1862; Location: Howletts, Virginia Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 26)
    Rudin # S - 584
  - Slave Amanda and Her Children are Auctioned, November 24, 1862; Format: MDocS (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 210
  - Slave Impressment Receipt for Three Negro Slaves Who Worked Eleven Days, December 11, 1862; Location: Russell County, Alabama Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 13, Folder 27)
    Rudin # S - 577
  - Pre-Printed Receipt for a Slave Girl, December 23, 1862; Location: Atlanta, Georgia Format: Ptd DOC (Box 13, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S - 383
  - Receipt for advertising sale of slaves, 1863; Location: Alabama (Box 13, Folder 29)
    Rudin # S - 121
  - Slave Bill of Sale-"Price to be determined at the close of the war", March 30, 1863; Location: Virginia (Box 13, Folder 30)
    Rudin # S - 72
  - Bill of Sale for a Slave Boy "who has run away with the Yankees", May 6, 1863; Format: MDocS (Box 13, Folder 31)
    Rudin # S - 459
  - Power of Attorney to Handle Monies due for Services of Slaves on the Defenses at Wilmington, North Carolina, May 11, 1863?; Location: Harnett County, North Carolina Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 13, Folder 32)
    Rudin # S - 362
  - Printed slave bill of sale - $5800 for five named slaves, June 9, 1863; Location: Richmond, Virginia Format: Ptd Doc (Box 13, Folder 33)
    Rudin # S - 660
  - Woman sells her slave, 1864; Location: Texas (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 31
  - Document Approving Pay for "Contraband Teamsters", April 1864; Location: Bridgeport, Alabama Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 41, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 400
  - Payment For Slave Made with Peas and Lard, April 7, 1864; Location: Marion District, South Carolina Format: MDocS (Box 13, Folder 34)
    Rudin # S - 414
  - Mississippi Confederate slave impressment receipt, January 19, 1865; Format: MDS (Box 13, Folder 34A)
    Rudin # S - 1040
  - Slave Dealer Offers Slaves for Sale, January 8, 1865; Location: Salisbury, North Carolina Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 35)
    Rudin # S - 519
  - Freed slaves will have to labor for their livelihood, April 27, 1865; Location: Raleigh, North Carolina Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 36)
    Rudin # S - 653
  - Nine Year Old Orphan "Freed Girl" Becomes Indentured Servant for Nine Years, January 22, 1866; Location: Walton County, Georgia Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 37)
    Rudin # S - 470
  - Letter from Maria Banks (an ex-slave) to Mr. A.J. Stephens requesting money and employment, September 6, 1875; Location: Norfolk, VA Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 36a)
  - John Drake slave ledger used to record expenses for the purchase, hire, and "maintenance" of slaves, 1830s-1850s (Volume 4681 Bd. Ms. 1)
  - James Eppinger slave ledger used to record expenses for the purchase, hire, and "maintenance" of slaves, 1818-1830 (Volume 4681 Bd. Ms. 2)
    Also includes manuscript copies of a verdict and public statements surrounding a court case concerning disputes of Frederick Selleck vs. Isaac Ruckhill, James Eppinger, and Dr. John P. Berthelot of Savannah, Georgia, over a free black man and woman whom Selleck allegedly confined and possibly intended to enslave.
- Series XVII: Slave Dealers, Slave Trading
  - Slave Dealer Advertising Cover - Oval Printed Corner Card, Location: New Orleans Format: ENV (Box 13, Folder 40)
    Rudin # S - 513
  - Slave Dealer Letter to General Anthony Wayne, June 1, 1785; Location: South Carolina Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 41)
    Rudin # S - 148
  - British Slave Trade Correspondence--"the profits outdo any South American Mine", January 4, 1798 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 74
  - Letter by two slave traders to their employer relaying information about a slave uprising in West Africa, January 15, 1808; Location: Ship "Hibernia" Format: ALS (Box 41, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 302
  - Slave Dealer Mentions the Slave Market and Refers to Two Slaves Who Have Run Away, February 8, 1820; Location: Jackson, Mississippi Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 42)
    Rudin # S - 492
  - Slave Trader Letter Discussing Loans, Purchases and the Slave Market, May 15, 1835; Location: Nashville, Tennessee Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 43)
    Rudin # S - 511
  - Slave dealer Joseph Meek describes high demand and rigors of market, September 27, 1835; Location: Livingston, Mississippi Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 44)
    Rudin # S - 646
  - Slave Auctioneers Handbill, ca.1840-1860; Location: Tennessee (Box 13, Folder 45)
    Rudin # S - 177
  - Three Autographed letters from Israel Randall, re: slave trade, December 1841-August 1842; Location: Brazil (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 107
  - Extracts from "General Instructions from A.P. Upsur to Comdr. Perry transmitted to Lt. A. Lewis", ca. 1843-1844; Format: MDocS (Box 18, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 306
  - Discusses Prospects of Opening a Slave Dealership, December 21, 1843; Location: Mobile, Alabama Format: ALS (Box 13, Folder 50)
    Rudin # S - 385
  - Letter from One Slave Trader to Another Requesting Slaves to be Sent on Consignment, December 8, 1847; Location: Charleston, SC Format: ALS (Box 40, Folder 38)
    Rudin # S - 556
  - Slave Speculator Wants to Make Sales Down South, August 21, 1848; Location: Mayesville, Kentucky Format: ALS (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 344
  - Slave Dealer's Business Card, ca. 1850; Location: Virginia (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 104
  - Slave Dealer's receipt book, 1850s; Location: Richmond, Virginia Format: Book (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 678
  - Slave Dealer's Letter, regarding current market, October 3, 1850; Location: Virginia Format: ALS (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 66
  - Slave dealer FW Watson writes of potential slave purchases and problems with a sale, October 20, 1851; Location: Dublin, North Carolina Format: ALS (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 993
  - Slave-seller allows families to remain together and the slaves to choose their new owners, January 27, 1852; Location: New York Format: ALS (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 255
  - Plantation Owner's Letter, regarding " the state of the Negro market", February 28, 1853; Location: Virginia (Box 14, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 90
  - Slave Trader's Letter, regarding "Can you sell any plough boys for me?", March 20, 1853; Location: Alabama (Box 14, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 70
  - Slave Dealer Letter to his partner--"Buy another little girl...", January 5, 1855; Location: Mississippi (Box 14, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 103
  - Buying Slaves in the Deep South, September 23, 1856; Location: Prairie Format: ALS (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 339
  - Slave Dealer's Letter, complaining about condition of slaves he wanted to sell, January 27, 1859; Location: Mississippi (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 192
  - Letter from a Slave Auctioneer (Davis and Deupree)--re: seeks consignments of slaves, June 20, 1860; Location: Virginia (Box 14, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 5
  - Slave Dealer's Price Listing, September 20, 1860; Location: Virginia (Box 14, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 41
  - Slavery Letter, regarding trading men for cattle and cotton, March 24, 1865; Location: Louisiana (Box 18, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 1
  - Letter and envelope from Slave Auctioneer (Davis and Deupree)--re: sale of slaves (Virginia), February 7, 1861 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Letter from Slave Dealer (J. Winbush Young)--re: purchased slaves being sent to E.H. Stokes, October 3, 1863 (Box 19, Folder 24)
- Series XVIII: Slave Taxation
  - Register- Tax on 14 Slaves Being Moved From GA to MD, January 2, 1839 (Box 40, Folder 39)
  - Slavery Tax Record Book, 1806; Location: Maryland (Box 18, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 153
  - Tax Ledger Showing Assessment Amounts on Slaves, Free Blacks, Livestock, Land and Personal Taxes, ca. 1815; Location: Cedar Creek, Sussex County, Delaware Format: Ledger (Box 18, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 469
  - Tax Ledger Lists Hundreds of Slaves, ca. 1840s; Location: Alabama? Format: Ledger (Box 14, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 432
  - Slave Tax Receipt, 1840; Location: Virginia (Box 14, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 16
  - Tax Receipt for Slaves, February 1851; Location: Tennessee (Box 14, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 81
  - Slave Tax Receipt, February 12, 1852; Location: Adams County, Mississippi Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 14, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 229
  - Virginia Slave Tax Document, ca. 1853-1854 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 75
  - Tax Receipt, 1856; Location: Sergeant City of Petersburg, Dr. (Box 14, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 91
  - Virginia Tax Bill Includes Tax on 21 Slaves, 1857; Location: Albemarle County, Virginia Format: Ptd DOC (Box 14, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 391
  - Tax bill Includes Tax on 15 Slaves and Freed Slaves, 1860; Location: Albermarle County, Virginia Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 14, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 491
  - Slave Taxation--Register of Births, 1858; Location: Virginia (Box 18, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 43
  - Tax Receipt, 1862; Location: Virginia (Box 14, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 98
  - Free Man Pays Tax on Himself and His Property, 1862; Location: Albemarle County, Virginia Format: Ptd DOC (Box 14, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 392
  - Tax Receipt for "6 heads of cattle…29 Slaves..", March 6, 1863; Location: Mississippi Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 14, Folder 24)
    Rudin # S - 547
  - Tax credit for stolen slaves, 1864; Location: Mississippi Format: MDoc (Box 14, Folder 25)
    Rudin # S - 55
- Series XIX: Stereoviews, Photographs, Postcards and Trading Cards
  - African American Chimney Sweeps Stereoview, Location: Savannah, Georgia Format: Stereoview (Box 14, Folder 26)
    Rudin # S - 517
  - Two stereoviews of slave pens, Location: Alexandria, Virginia Format: Stereoview (Box 14, Folder 26A)
    Rudin # S - 1050
  - African American child holding Kepi, Location: Washington, DC Format: Carte de Visite (Box 14, Folder 26B)
    Rudin # S - 1051
  - Photograph of a Black Boy Preacher, Location: Canal Street, New Orleans Format: Cabinet Card (Box 14, Folder 27)
    Rudin # S - 590
  - Tinted carte-de-visite by J.P. Soule of G.G. Fish's work "Emancipation", Format: Carte-de-visite (Box 13, Folder 36a)
  - The Conjoined Slave Twins - "The Two-Headed Nightingale", Location: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania Format: CDV (Box 14, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S - 370
  - 3 postcards with African American baptism, Sheridan Home School, and cotton picking, Location: North Carolina Format: Photo postcards (Box 14, Folder 29)
    Rudin # S - 712
  - 7 photographs of African American men women and children picking cotton, Location: Tennessee Format: Photographs (Box 14, Folder 30)
    Rudin # S - 818
  - Federal soldier with his young black servant, Format: CDV (Box 14, Folder 31)
    Rudin # S - 860
  - "All the Live Stock on Mr. Gill's Plantation after the Battle of Gettysburgh", Format: Stereoview (Box 14, Folder 32)
    Rudin # S - 900
  - 3 stereoviews of black field hands picking cotton, Location: Mississippi, Georgia Format: Stereoview (Box 14, Folder 33)
    Rudin # S - 1024
  - Fourteen Currier and Ives comic post cards, in color, 1778-1880; Location: New York Format: Post cards (Box 36)
    Rudin # S - 731
  - Carte de Visite Photograph of Sumner Plus an AQS, March 18, 1854; Location: Washington, DC Format: Photo (Box 14, Folder 34)
    Rudin # S - 505
  - Stereoview #1362 "Picking Cotton, Georgia" Stereoview #6946 "Morning Start in Cotton Field", ca. 1860; Format: Stereoview (Box 14, Folder 35)
    Rudin # S - 136, 137
  - Stereoview #6947 "Cotton Picking in Full Blast" Stereoview #6951 "Pickers Grouped in Cotton Blast", ca. 1860; Format: Stereoview (Box 14, Folder 36)
    Rudin # S - 138, 139
  - Stereoview #9506 "We's Done all dis s'morning" Stereoview #6512 "Plowing the Field for Cotton", ca. 1860; Format: Stereoview (Box 14, Folder 37)
    Rudin # S - 140, 141
  - Stereoview #12479 "Cotton! Levee, New Orleans" Stereoview #V232341 "Plantation Pickers Work, Georgia, ca. 1860; Format: Stereoview (Box 14, Folder 38)
    Rudin # S - 142, 143
  - Young Slave Child, 1863; Location: Hartford, Connecticut Format: CDV (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 270
  - "Slave Auction", 1864; Location: New York Format: CDV (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 389
  - Five views of the "Slave Children from New Orleans", 1864; Format: CDV (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 859
  - Staged CDV tableau "Education is Wealth...slaves from New Orleans", 1864; Location: S. Tackaberry, New York Format: CDV (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 807
  - Photograph of Slave Children at Play - Photo Probably Taken on a Plantation in the Baton Rouge, Louisiana area, ca. Mid-1860s; Format: Photograph (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 593
  - Four theatre cards promoting "Uncle Tom's Cabin", 1880s; Location: Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania Format: Ptd Cards (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 813
  - Six uncut black farmer trade cards press sheet, 1880s; Format: Press sheet (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 816
  - Four black trade cards depicting sports, 1880s; Format: Trade cards (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 913
  - St. Louis beef advertisement featuring stereotype black dialect, 1890s; Location: St. Louis Format: Trade cards (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 947
  - Black cotton warehouse workers numbering bales; worker outside a factory's cotton gin, 1890; Format: Photographs (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 998
  - Twenty five stereoviews, 1892-1903 (Box 36)
    Rudin # S - 604
  - Elderly black man seated with a white female child on his lap, 1895; Location: New York Format: Stereoview (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 971
  - Two prints of Africa Americans, titled "Gimme de Rine" and "Last One In's a Nigger", Location: McCrary and Branson, Knoxville Tennessee Format: Photograph prints (Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 603
  - Eleven cards commemorating the Emancipation Proclamation, ca. 1909; Location: Germany Format: Post cards (Box 15, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 931
  - Color postcard showing African Americans toiling in a large field, titled "Picking Cotton", ca. 1910; Format: Post card (Box 15, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 796
  - "Kansas City Sun" promotional photograph of Jno. W. "Blind" Boone and his manager, December 5, 1914; Format: Photograph (Box 15, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 843
  - Black American accordian postcards "Greetings from the Happy South", ca. 1920; Format: Post cards (Box 15, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 817
- Series XX: Objects
  - Uncle Tom's Cabin bandana depicting scenes, Format: Bandanna (Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 938
  - Meerschaum Pipe in the form of the head of a female slave, showing detailed coiffure and headdress, Format: Pipe (Box 29)
    Rudin # S - 698
  - Meerschaum Pipe carved head with beard and gold loop in right ear, Format: Pipe (Box 29)
    Rudin # S - 810
  - West African wrought iron slave 'coffle', Location: West Africa Format: Coffle (Box 32)
    Rudin # S - 902
  - Token used to count the crop picked by hired cotton pickers, Location: Halethorpe, Maryland Format: Token (Box 15, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 685
  - Pair of wrought iron "middle passage" slave shackles for a woman or a young man, early 1800s (Box 32)
    Rudin # S - 875
  - Runaway Slave Woodblock carving, with print, Ca. 1820-1840; Format: Woodblock (Box 28)
    Rudin # S - 179
  - One Cent American Colonization Token, 1833; Format: Token (Box 28)
    Rudin # S - 187
  - Slave Auctioneer's Token, South Carolina, 1846; Format: Token (Box 28)
    Rudin # S - 172
  - Slave Tag, 1856; Location: Charleston, South Carolina (Box 28)
    Rudin # S - 152
  - Anti-Slavery Token "May Slavery and Oppression Cease Throughout the World", Format: Coin (Box 15, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 476
  - New Orleans slave plantation supply store token -authenticity questionable, Format: Token (Box 15, Folder 16A)
    Rudin # S - 1029
  - Decorated Bracelet Token ("Manila") Used as Slave Barter with African Chieftains, ca. 1750-1850; Location: Nigeria, West Africa (Box 33)